Guide to the Fales Portrait/Subject Collection ca. 1800 - 1998 MSS.034
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales Library and Special Collections Portrait Collection
circa 1800-Present
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales Library
MSS.034
6 Linear Feet in 6 boxes
The Portrait/Subject Collection consists of portraits and photographs of American and British authors, as well as a smaller number depicting actors, from the nineteenth and twentieth centuries.
Provenance
This collection of portraits, photographs, sketches, and author-related materials has been acquired and archived by various Fales librarians and staff members since 1957.
Scope and Content Note
The contents of the Portrait/Subject Collection are primarily portraits, most of which are devoted to American and British authors and thespians from the nineteenth and twentieth centuries with a much smaller quantity depicting European monarchs and politicians. There are also materials regarding artists such as Claude Monet and Fairfield Porter, as well as images of various composers, the American Church in Rome, New York City, and Paris. Of particular interest are two Plans for the City of New York covering the southern end of Manhattan, which are dated 1797 (an 1853 re-print) and 1807, as well as several original American West Posters announcing rewards for wanted outlaws dating from the early twentieth century.
While many of the documents are photographs, a considerable number are printed images such as engravings and lithographs cut from nineteenth and twentieth-century publications, advertisements, maps, postcards, book plates, and posters. Some of the files dedicated to authors also hold textual material such as reviews, advertisements, news paper clippings, or, in very rare cases, copies of their writing.
Arrangement
The Portrait/Subject Collection consists of a single series numbered consecutively in six boxes and one oversize flat box. No subject division is necessary. The contents are arranged in alphabetical order by either the subject or the last name of the person's portrait.
Because of the number of archivists on this project and the original disarray of the collection, the collection is somewhat disorderly in its alphabetical order. A majority of the archival folders contain materials for more than one heading. Multiple headings are indicated on each folder and within the Box and Folder List itself.
Missing Title
Series I
Oversize
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Newsletters.; Exhibition catalogs.; Photocopies.; Scores.; Postcards.; Photographs.; Direct mail.; Business cards.; Book jackets.; Imperial photographs.; Advertisements.; Wanted posters.; Lithographs.; Cabinet photographs.; Posters.; Cartes-de-visite (card photographs); Leaflets (printed works); Engravings (prints); Bookplates.; Pamphlets.; Fillmore Auditorium (San Francisco, Calif.); New York (N.Y.).; Authors, American |y 20th century |x Portraits.; Great Britain |x Kings and rulers |x Portraits.; Europe |x Kings and rulers |x Portraits.; Portrait photography |z Great Britain.; English prose literature.; Authors, English |y 19th century |x Portraits.; Authors, English |y 20th century |x Portraits.; Authors, American |y 19th century |x Portraits.; Poets |x Portraits.; American literature.; English literature.; Portrait prints |y 19th century.; Queens |z Great Britain |x Portraits.; Authors |x Portraits.; Actors |x Portraits.; Portrait prints |y 20th century.; Portrait Photography |z United States.; Portrait prints, American |y 19th century.; Portrait Prints, British.; Portrait Prints, European.; Printing |z England |x History |y 19th century.; Printing |z England |x History |y 20th century.; Printing |z United States |x History |y 19th century.; Printing |z United States |x History |y 20th century.; Printing |z Europe |x History.; Architectural drawings (visual works); Photogravures (prints); Clippings (information artifacts); Cunningham, Allan, 1784-1842; Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1803-1882; MacDiarmid, Hugh, 1892-1978; Haggard, H. Rider (Henry Rider), 1856-1925; Cobb, Irvin S. (Irvin Shrewsbury), 1876-1944; Colker, Ed, 1927-; Collins, Wilkie, 1824-1889; Cone, Helen Gray, 1859-; Caine, Hall, Sir, 1853-1931; Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881; Chambers, Robert, 1802-1871; Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1835-1910; Bennett, Arnold, 1867-1931; Bryant, William Cullen, 1794-1878; Byron, George Gordon Byron, Baron, 1788-1824; Cabell, James Branch, 1879-1958; Baillie, Joanna, 1762-1851; Auden, W.H. (Wystan Hugh), 1907-1973; Beerbohm, Max, Sir, 1872-1956; Barrie, J. M. (James Matthew), 1860-1937; Antin, Eleanor; Angelou, Maya; Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892; Wolfe, Thomas, 1900-1938; Wilde, Oscar, 1854-1900; Wellington, Arthur Wellesley, Duke of, 1769-1852; Wells, H. G. (Herbert George), 1866-1946; Victoria, Queen of Great Britain, 1819-1901; Walpole, Hugh, Sir, 1884-1941; Thoreau, Henry David, 1817-1862; Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, Baron, 1809-1892; Shaw, Bernard, 1856-1950; Scott, Walter, 1771-1832; Ruskin, John, 1819-1900; Prophet; Porter, Fairfield; Morgan, Lady (Sydney), 1783-1859; Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852; Mitchell, S. Weir (Silas Weir), 1829-1914; Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1807-1882; Lawrence, D. H. (David Herbert), 1885-1930; Kipling, Rudyard, 1865-1936; Kaprow, Allan; Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920; Hawthorne, Nathaniel, 1804-1864
- Series I
  - Aberdeen, George Hamilton, 4th Earl of Abringer, James Adams, Charles F. Adams, John [Adams, Francis], Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adelaide, Duchess of Clarence Agee, James Ainsworth, William Harrison, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Albert, Prince; Alcott, Louisa May Aldington, Richard, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alexander I, Emperor of Russia Alison, Archibald, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Allen, James Lane Alvardo y Bracomonte, Don Juan, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Church in Rome (proposed design), Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American West: Posters, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    General note
    Includes wanted posters for Billy the Kid, Black Bart, Jesse James, and other outlaws
  - Amis, Kingsley Andre, Major John Andrews, James Andrews, Miles, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Angelou, Maya Anglesey, Arthur, 1st Earl Anglesey, Marquis of Anonymous, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Anne, Queen Antin, Eleanor Archer, Samuel Arnold, Sir Edward, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Arnold, Mathew Arnold, Thomas Arunde, Countess, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ashmole, Elias Astle, Thomas Athanase, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Atherton, Gertrude Auckland, George E., Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Auchincloss, Louis, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Auden, W. H., Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Audubon, John Augustus, Caius Julius Caesar Austin, Mrs. Alfred Aytoun, Edmonstoune, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bachellor, Irving Bacon, Sir Francis Baily, Philip James, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Baillie, Joanna, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Baker, Russell Balzac, Honore de Bancroft, George, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Banks, Joseph; Banks, Russell Barber, Francis, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Barham, Richard Harris (Thomas Ingoldsby), Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Barrie, Sir James, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Includes an autographed image of J.M. Barrie pluse autographed postcards depicting Seymour Hicks and Arthur Cleave
  - Barrington, Daines Barrymore, Ethel Barrymore, John; Barzun, Jacques, Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bauer, Jerry, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bates, H. E. Barth, John Baum, Vicki Beattie, James, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bayly, Thomas H. Beaconsfield, Benjamin Beaulieu, Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Beardsley, Aubrey, Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Beckford,William Bedford, John Beebe, Charles William, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Beerbohm, Sir Max, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Beechey, Sir William, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Belle-Isle, Nicolas Fouquet Bellow, Saul, Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Benger, Elizabeth Bennett, Arnold, Undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Berger, Edgar Bergman, Andrew Berchem, Nicholas, Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Bennett, Arnold, Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bennet, Henry Grey Benson, Edward Bentham, Jeremy, Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Berge, Carol Berger, Thomas Bernadotte Berrigan, Ted Berry, Wendell, Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Besant, Walter and Annie, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Bessborough, Fredrick, Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Bexley, Nicholas Biddle, Francis Birrell, Augustine, Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Black, Joseph Black, William Blackburn, Paul, Undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Blackmore, Sir Richard Blackwell, Sir William Blair, Hugh Blanchard, Samuel Laman, Undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Blessington, Marguerite Countess of, Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Bloomfield, Robert Blücher, Gebhard Lebereeht von, Prince of Wahlstadt Bodley, Sir Thomas, Undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Boileau, Nicholas Bompelli, P. Bonaparte, Louis Napoléon Bonaparte, Lucien, Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Book Auction Prints, Undated (Box 1, Folder 44A)
  - Booth, Charles Booth, Edwin, Undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Borrow, George, Undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Boscawen, Admiral Bosschere, Jean de Bossvet, Jacques Benigne, Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Boswell, James, Undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Boucher, François, Undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Boucicault, Dion Boulton, Matthew, Undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Bourbon, Jean de Boydell, John Boyle, Robert, Undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Bowles, William Lisle Bowring, John, Undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Braham, [John] Of Rowan Brindley, James Brinnin, John Malcolm Bromfield, Louis, Undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Brooke, Frances (Moore) Brooke, Gustavus Vaughan, Undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Brougham and Vaux, Henry Peter Brougham, Baron of, Undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Brown, Jacob Jennings Brown, Dr. John Brown, Rita Mae, Undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Browning, Elizabeth Barrett Browning, Robert Brownmiller, Susan, Undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Brunel, Sir Max Isambard Bryant, Jacob Bryant, William Cullen, Undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Bryce, James Bryee Brydges, Sir Samuel Egerton, Undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Buck, Pearl S. Buckingham, George Villiers, 1st Duke of Buckstone, John Baldwin Buonaroti, Michael Angelo, Undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Burder, George Burdett, Sir Francis Burgess, Anthony Burghley, William Cecil, Undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Burke, Edmund, Undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Burlington, Richard Boyle, Earl of Burnet, Gilbert, Bishop of Salisbury, Undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Burns, Robert, Undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Burr, Jane, Undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Burroughs, John Burroughs, William, Undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Bynner, Witter, Undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Byron, George Gordon Noël, Baron, Undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Cabell, James Branch, Undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Caesar, Gaius Julius, Undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Caine, Sir Hall, Undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Camden, Lord Camden, William Cambell, Archibald, Undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Campbell, Mrs. Patrick, Undated (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Campbell, Thomas, Undated (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Canning, George, Undated (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Caroline, Consort of George II (or Caroline, Amelia Elizabeth, consort of George IV), Undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Carascci, A[gostino] Carlisle, Frederick Honard, 5th Earl of, Undated (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Carlyle, Thomas Carver, Raymond Cary, Alice Cary, Joyce, Undated (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Carroll, John Br. Carter, Angela Carter, Elizabeth, Undated (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Castlereagh, Robert Stewart, Viscount, Undated (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Catallus, [Gauis Valerlus] Catherine, Undated (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Chalmers, George Chalmers, Thomas, Undated (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Chambers, Robert Chappel, Alonzo, Undated (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Charlemont, James Caulfeild, 1st Earl of Charles, Archduke of Austria, Undated (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Charles II, King of Great Britain, Undated (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Charlotte, Arthur Charlotte, Augusta, Princess of Saxe-Coburg Charlotte, Sophia, Consort of King George III, Undated (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Charnwood, Godfrey Rathbone Benson, Baron Charyn, Jerome, Undated (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Chase, Pauline Chateaubriand, François René, Viscount de, Undated (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Chatham, William Pitt Chauncey, Charles Chelmsford, Lord (Lord High Chancellor of Great Britain), Undated (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Chesterton, Gilbert Keith, Undated (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Chouduri, Pradip, Undated (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Churchill, Charles Churchill, Winston Leonard Spencer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Clarendon, George William Frederick Villiers, 4th Earl of Clarendon, John Charles Villiers, 3rd Earl of, Undated (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, Undated (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Cleopatra Clifden, Henry Welbore Agar Ellis, Undated (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Cobb, Irvin Shewsbury, Undated (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Cobbett, William Cobden, Richard Cocteau, Jean, Undated (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Cochrane, Captain Lord Coke, Sir Edward Colchester, Charles Abbot, Baron, Undated (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Colker, Ed, Undated (Box 1, Folder 99)
    Includes an exhibition catalog for "The First Decade" at the Center for Book Arts
  - Coleridge, Samuel Taylor, Undated (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Collins, Wilkie, Undated (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Colman, George Colman, George, the Younger, Undated (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Colquhoun, Patrick Compton-Burnett, I., Undated (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Composers: Berlioz, Hector Debussy, Claude Mendelssohn Stravinsky, Undated (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Condon, Richard Cone, Helen Grey, Undated (Box 1, Folder 105)
    This folder's Helen Grey Cone material consists of poems, two signatures cut from letters, articles, and someone's handwritten transcripts/ notes regarding her poems.
  - Condé, Louis I, Prince of Bourbon Conrad, Joseph Conroy, Frank Conyngham, William, Undated (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Cook, Captain Cook, Eliza Cooke, George Frederick Cooke, John Horne, Undated (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Coote, Lieut. Gen. Sir Eyre Copley, John Singelton, Undated (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Cornwallis, Jemima Tullikens Cornwall, Barry, Undated (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Cotton, Nathaniel Coutts, Angelou Coward, Noël Cowper, William, Undated (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Cozzens, Fred Cozzens, James Gould Crabbe, George Crammer, Thomas, Archbishop of Canterbury, Undated (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - Crawford, Francis Marion, Undated (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - Creswick, Thomas Cruden, Alexander Cumberland, Richard, Undated (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Cullen, Countee, Undated (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Cunningham, Allan, Undated (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Currie, James Curtis, George William Cushman, Charlotte, Undated (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Cuvier (aka John Murray Hunter), Undated (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Dahl, Michael Dale, Richard, Undated (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Dalrymple, Alexander Damer, Anne Seymour (Conway) Dane, Clemence, Undated (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Daniel,George Dante Darwin, Charles, Undated (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - Davenport, E. L. Dell, Floyd Demby, William Denman, T., Undated (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Derby, Edward Henry Stanley, 15th Earl of, Undated (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - DeVere, Aubrey Devonshire, Charles Blount Devonshire, Edward, Undated (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Devonshire, Georgiana (Spenser) Cavendish, Duchess of Devonshire, William Cavendish, 1st Earl of, Undated (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Dewhurst, Miss Dickenson, Emily, Undated (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Diana of Poictiers Digby, Sir Kenelm Di Prima, Diane, Undated (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Disreali, Benjamin Disreali, Isaac, Undated (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - Dixon, William Hepworth, Undated (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - Dobson, William, Undated (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - Dodge, George Jason, Undated (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - Donleavy, J.P. Donoughmore, John Hely-Hutchinson, 2nd Earl of, Undated (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Doran, John, Undated (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - Doughty, Charles M., Undated (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Douglas, Lord Alfred Bruce, Undated (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - Dow, Gerard, Undated (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Doyle, Sir Arthur Conan, Undated (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Doyle, Sir Francis Hastings Charles, 2nd Bart., Undated (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Drake, Sir Francis, Undated (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Draper, Sir William, Undated (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Dreiser, Theodore, Undated (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Dresser, Paul Drinkwater, John, Undated (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Dryden, John, Undated (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Dugdale, Stephen, Undated (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - Dumas, Alexandre, Undated (Box 2, Folder 144)
  - DuMaurier, George Louis, Undated (Box 2, Folder 145)
  - DuMaurier, Gerard, Undated (Box 2, Folder 146)
  - Duncannon, Lady, Undated (Box 2, Folder 147)
  - Duncombe, Thomas Slingsby, Undated (Box 2, Folder 148)
  - Durham, Louisa Elizabeth (Grey), Baroness, Undated (Box 2, Folder 149)
  - Durrell, Lawrence, Undated (Box 2, Folder 150)
  - Dusenbery, Gail, Undated (Box 2, Folder 151)
    Contains one poem, "The Sea Gull," for Oyez
  - Eddington, Sir Arthur, Undated (Box 2, Folder 152)
  - Edelinck, Gerard Edgeworth, Maria, Undated (Box 2, Folder 153)
  - Egg, Augustus [Leopold], Undated (Box 2, Folder 154)
  - Eggleston, George Cary, Undated (Box 2, Folder 155)
  - Eliot, Charles, Undated (Box 2, Folder 156)
  - Eliot, George (Mary Ann Evans) Eliot, T.S., Undated (Box 2, Folder 157)
  - Elizabeth, Princess of England, Undated (Box 2, Folder 158)
  - Elizabeth, Queen of England and Ireland, Undated (Box 2, Folder 159)
  - Ellice, Lady Hannah, Undated (Box 2, Folder 160)
  - Ellis, Bret Easton, Undated (Box 2, Folder 161)
  - Ellison, Ralph, Undated (Box 2, Folder 162)
  - Elliston, Robert William, Undated (Box 2, Folder 163)
  - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, Undated (Box 2, Folder 164)
  - "Emigrants Farewell to Ireland", Undated (Box 2, Folder 165)
  - English Church in Rome (proposed design), Undated (Box 2, Folder 166)
  - Engravings Enslin, Ted, Undated (Box 2, Folder 167)
  - Epicurus, Undated (Box 2, Folder 168)
  - Erdrich, Louise Ernest, Augustus, King of Hanover, Undated (Box 2, Folder 169)
  - Erskine, John, Undated (Box 2, Folder 170)
  - Erskine, Undated (Box 2, Folder 171)
  - Essex, Catherine Stephens, Countess of, Undated (Box 2, Folder 172)
  - Evelyn, John, Undated (Box 2, Folder 173)
  - Everett, Edward, Undated (Box 2, Folder 174)
  - Fantin-Latour, Ignace Henri Jean Théodore, Undated (Box 2, Folder 175)
  - Farmer, Richard, Undated (Box 2, Folder 176)
  - Faraday, Michael, Undated (Box 2, Folder 177)
  - Farquhar, John, Undated (Box 2, Folder 178)
  - Farrar, Fredric William, Undated (Box 2, Folder 179)
  - Farrell, James T. Farren, William, Undated (Box 2, Folder 180)
  - Fay, Theodore S. Ferguson, Sir Ronald [Craufund] Fern, Fanny Ferro, Robert, Undated (Box 2, Folder 181)
  - Few, William, Undated (Box 2, Folder 182)
  - Field, Richard, Undated (Box 2, Folder 183)
  - Fielding, Henry, Undated (Box 2, Folder 184)
  - Fields, James Thomas, Undated (Box 2, Folder 185)
  - Filmore East, Undated (Box 2, Folder 186A)
  - Filmore West, Undated (Box 2, Folder 186B)
  - Miscellaneous Mailers, Undated (Box 2, Folder 186C)
    The contents of 1861, 186B, and 186C were once part of one overfull folder, which is why 186C is out of alphabetical order. Contents composed of direct mail advertisements for Prophet (selling posters and postcards), Varsity House Inc., and Fillmore Records.
  - Fitzgerald, Edward, Undated (Box 2, Folder 187)
  - Fitzwilliam, William Wentworth, 2nd Earl of, Undated (Box 2, Folder 188)
  - Fixel, Lawrence, Undated (Box 2, Folder 189)
  - Flatman, Thomas, Undated (Box 2, Folder 190)
  - Fletcher, Joannes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 191)
  - Folkes, Martin, Undated (Box 2, Folder 192)
  - Forster, John, Undated (Box 2, Folder 193)
  - Fortescue, Sir John William, Undated (Box 2, Folder 194)
  - Fox, Charles James, Undated (Box 2, Folder 195)
  - France, Anatole Francis, John W, Undated (Box 2, Folder 196)
  - Frank, Waldo Frankau, Pamela, Undated (Box 2, Folder 197)
  - Franklin, Benjamin, Undated (Box 2, Folder 198)
  - Freeman, Edward Augustus Freeman, H.W. Freud, Sigmund Friedman, Bruce Jay, Undated (Box 2, Folder 199)
  - Frost, Barbara Frost, Frances M. Frost, Robert, Undated (Box 2, Folder 200)
  - Froude, James Anthony, Undated (Box 2, Folder 201)
  - Fuselli, Henry, Undated (Box 2, Folder 202)
  - Gale, Zona Gallatin, Abraham Alfonse Albert, Undated (Box 2, Folder 203)
  - Galsworthy, John, Undated (Box 2, Folder 204)
  - Galzy, Jeanne Galt, John, Undated (Box 2, Folder 205)
  - Garrick, David, Undated (Box 2, Folder 206)
  - Garrick, Mrs. David Garrigue, Jean, Undated (Box 2, Folder 207)
  - Gaskell, Elizabeth, Undated (Box 2, Folder 208)
  - Gautier, Theopile, Undated (Box 2, Folder 209)
  - Geheeb, Paul Gelhorn, Martha Genet, Janet Flanner, Undated (Box 2, Folder 210)
  - George I, King of Great Britain, Undated (Box 2, Folder 211)
    Also includes images of Edward I, George III, and George Augustus Frederick (Prince of Wales)
  - Gheeraerts, Marcus, Undated (Box 2, Folder 212)
  - Gibbon, Edward, Undated (Box 2, Folder 213)
  - Gibbons, Grinling, Undated (Box 2, Folder 214)
  - Gibbs, James Gibbs, Sir Philip, Undated (Box 2, Folder 215)
  - Gide, Andre, Undated (Box 2, Folder 216)
  - Gilbert, Marie Dolores Eliza Rosana, Undated (Box 2, Folder 217)
  - Gillette, William Gilliatt, Penelope Gilman, Mildred Ginsberg, Allen, Undated (Box 2, Folder 218)
  - Gladstone, William Ewart Glaspell, Susan, Undated (Box 2, Folder 219)
  - Glyn, Elinor (Sutherland), Undated (Box 2, Folder 220)
  - Godden, Rumer Godwin, Gail Godwin, Mary Wollstonecraft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 221)
  - Godwin, William, Undated (Box 2, Folder 222)
  - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, Undated (Box 2, Folder 223)
  - Gold, Herbert Golding, William Goldsmith, Oliver, Undated (Box 2, Folder 224)
  - Gordimer, Nadine Gordon, Caroline Gordon, Lord George, Undated (Box 2, Folder 225)
  - Gordon, Robert, Undated (Box 2, Folder 226)
  - Gorman, Herbert, Undated (Box 2, Folder 227)
  - Gossart, Jan, Undated (Box 2, Folder 228)
  - Gosse, Philip Henry, Undated (Box 2, Folder 229)
  - Goudge, Elizabeth; Gould, Gerald; Gould, Jean, Undated (Box 2, Folder 230)
  - Gould, Joe - portrait (Box 2, Folder 230b)
  - Goupy, Lewis, Undated (Box 2, Folder 231)
  - Graham, A.W., Undated (Box 2, Folder 232)
  - Graham, Robert Bontine Cunninghame, Undated (Box 2, Folder 233)
  - Granville, George Leveson-Gower, 2nd Earl of, Undated (Box 2, Folder 234)
  - Granville-Barker, Harley, Undated (Box 2, Folder 235)
  - Graspell, Susan Graves, Robert Gray, Thomas, Undated (Box 2, Folder 236)
  - Green, Julien Greene, Ward Greenhill, John, Undated (Box 2, Folder 237)
  - Greig, Maysie, Undated (Box 2, Folder 238)
  - Grenville, William Wyndham, Lord of, Undated (Box 2, Folder 239)
  - Grenville, Thomas, Undated (Box 2, Folder 240)
  - Grey, Charles, 1st Earl of, Undated (Box 2, Folder 241)
  - Grey, Charles, Undated (Box 2, Folder 242)
  - Grey, Zane, Undated (Box 2, Folder 243)
  - Grieve, Christopher Murray, Undated (Box 2, Folder 244)
  - Griswold, Rufus, Undated (Box 2, Folder 245)
  - Grose, Francis, Undated (Box 2, Folder 246)
  - Gross, Ronald, Undated (Box 2, Folder 247)
    Needs Conservation
  - Grover, Bernard, Undated (Box 2, Folder 248)
  - Grünewald, E., Undated (Box 2, Folder 249)
  - Guicciolli, Countess Guildford, Francis North, Baron, Undated (Box 2, Folder 250)
  - Guiney, Louise Imogen, Undated (Box 2, Folder 251)
  - Guiterman, Arthur Gulley, Undated (Box 2, Folder 252)
  - Habberton, John, Undated (Box 2, Folder 253)
  - Haggard, Sir Henry Rider, Undated (Box 2, Folder 254)